Preliminary Guide to the Guillermo F. Pardo de Leygonier Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Guillermo F. Pardo de Leygonier papers
1949-1977
MS 1384
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
Selected letters to Pardo de Leygonier as cultural associate of the Venezuelan Embassy in Paris.
Pardo de Leygonier, G. F.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ana Pardo P. to the Latin American Collection, 1983-.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Selected letters to Pardo de Leygonier as cultural associate of the Venezuelan Embassy in Paris.
Latin America; Diplomats; Pardo de Leygonier, G. F.
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  Donated by Ana M. Pardo P., first to the Latin American Collection and later to Manuscripts and Archives, in numerous accessions, beginning in May 1983.
  - Adds. 1983 May -1985 Nov.
    - Selected letters to Pardo de Leygonier as cultural associate of the Venezuelan Embassy in Paris, Circa 1949-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
    - Letters to G.F. Pardo de Leygonier from: (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - the authors Augusto Mijares, G. Humberto Mata, and others, 1959-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - Enrique Bernardo Nunes, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - M.A. Pulido Mendez, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - Alfonso Meejia Robledo, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - G. Georges-Picot, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - Alberto Jochamorvitz, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - Rodolfo Auvert, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - Mario Briceno Perozo, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
      - Raul Soules Baldo (letters and photographs), 1963-1965, 1968-1975, 1970-1971, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
    - Additional letters to G.F. Pardo de Leygonier from G. Humberto Mata, 1968-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
    - Additional letters to G.F. Pardo de Leygonier from G. Humberto Mata and Oliver Baulny, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
    - TLS to Ana Pardo P. from G. Humberto Mata, 1977 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
    - Ms "L'Amoureuse Amitie du General Miranda et de Madame Petion de Villeneuve," by Pardo de Leygonier, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 12)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 14)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence and papers, 1898-1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)